<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-12-01T11:57:10-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Hyde</title><subtitle>A brazen two-column &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; theme that pairs a prominent sidebar with uncomplicated content. Made by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mdo&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@mdo&lt;/a&gt;.</subtitle><author><name>Mark Otto</name></author><entry><title type="html">Sample Post</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2012/02/06/whats-jekyll/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sample Post" /><published>2012-02-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2012-02-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2012/02/06/whats-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2012/02/06/whats-jekyll/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; is a static site generator, an open-source tool for creating simple yet powerful websites of all shapes and sizes. From &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/blob/master/README.markdown&quot;&gt;the project’s readme&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Jekyll is a simple, blog aware, static site generator. It takes a template directory […] and spits out a complete, static website suitable for serving with Apache or your favorite web server. This is also the engine behind GitHub Pages, which you can use to host your project’s page or blog right here from GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s an immensely useful tool and one we encourage you to use here with Hyde.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find out more by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll&quot;&gt;visiting the project on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mark Otto</name></author><summary type="html">Jekyll is a static site generator, an open-source tool for creating simple yet powerful websites of all shapes and sizes. From the project’s readme: Jekyll is a simple, blog aware, static site generator. It takes a template directory […] and spits out a complete, static website suitable for serving with Apache or your favorite web server. This is also the engine behind GitHub Pages, which you can use to host your project’s page or blog right here from GitHub. It’s an immensely useful tool and one we encourage you to use here with Hyde. Find out more by visiting the project on GitHub.</summary></entry></feed>